新浪微博 @摆渡字幕组 译制
关注微博 掌握最新字幕资源
翻译：金鹏 & 我是饭饭
翻译：surui & 寶貝ル
翻译：Spirit Breaker & 小鱼
翻译：不酸的柠檬 & 张天烊
校对：Spirit Breaker
摆渡字幕组翻译招募中 报名群:377256405
乔乔·贝茨勒
Jojo Betzler.
十岁
Ten years old.
今天你正式入伍青年团
Today you join the ranks of the Jungvolk,
要度过一个特别的训练周末
in a very special training weekend.
你将面临高强度的训练 但在今天
It's going to be intense, but today
你会成为一个男子汉
you become a man.
我发誓把我所有的精力和力量都奉献给救世主
I swear to devote all my energies and my strength to the savior of our country -
阿道夫·希特勒
Adolf Hitler.
我时刻甘愿为他抛头颅 洒热血
I am willing and ready to give up my life for him,
上帝保佑
so help me God.
好的 这就对了
Yes, that's right.
-那么乔乔·贝茨勒 你的思想如何  -敏锐如蛇
- Now, Jojo Betzler, what is your mind? - Snake mind.
-乔乔·贝茨勒 你的身体如何  -结实如狼
- And Jojo Betzler, what is your body? - Wolf body.
-乔乔·贝茨勒 你的勇气如何  -无畏如豹
- Jojo Betzler, what is your courage? - Panther courage.
-乔乔·贝茨勒 你的灵魂如何  -德国英魂
- And Jojo Betzler, what is your soul? - A German soul.
是的 伙计 你已经准备好了
Yeah, man, you're ready.
阿道夫
Adolf?
我想我做不到
I don't think I can do this.
谁说的 你当然可以
Was? Of course, you can!
虽然你有点骨瘦如柴 不受欢迎
Sure, you're a little bit scrawny and a bit unpopular,
甚至十岁了连鞋带都不会系
and you can't tie your shoelaces even though you're ten years old.
但你依旧是我见过的最优秀 最忠诚的小纳粹
But you're still, the bestest, most loyal little Nazi I've ever met.
更别说你长得还这么好看
Not to mention the fact you're really good-looking.
所以你要出去好好享受快乐时光 好吗
So, you gonna get out there and you gonna have a great time, okay?
-好吧  -这就是精神 好的
- Okay. - That's the spirit! Okay.
跟我喊万岁
Heil me, man.
希特勒万岁
Heil Hitler.
啥 你可以喊得更好的
Whaat? You can heil me better than that.
希特勒万岁
Heil Hitler.
扔掉思想包袱 别去想它
Just throw it away, don't even think about that.
-希特勒万岁  -不 你还是想太多了
- Heil Hitler. - No, you're over thinking it.
-希特勒万岁  -希特勒万岁
- Heil Hitler. - Heil Hiteler.
谁是希特勒  你会说德语吗
Who's Hiteler? Do you even speak German?
-希特勒万岁  -那不是欢呼 这才是
- Heil Hitler! - That's not the heil, this is the heil -
-万岁  -希特勒万岁
- Heil! - Heil Hitler!
希特勒万岁
Heil Hitler!
就这样 你明白了 希特勒万岁 祝你有美好的一天
That's it, you got it. Heil Hitler! Have a great day.
希特勒万岁 你会是最优秀的
Heil Hitler! You gonna be the best.
希特勒万岁 你能做到的
Heil Hitler! You can do it.
希特勒万岁
Heil Hitler!
♪哦 来吧 来我这里♪
♪ Oh, komm doch, komm zu Mir ♪
♪你把我带走了♪
♪ Du nimmst Mir den Verstand ♪
♪哦 来吧 来我这里♪
♪ Oh, komm doch, komm zu Mir ♪
♪来 把手给我♪
♪ Komm, gib Mir deine Hand ♪
♪噢 你是如此的美丽♪
♪ Oh, Du bist so schön ♪
♪美的像钻石♪
♪ Schön wie ein Diamant ♪
♪我想和你一起去♪
♪ Ich will mit Dir gehen ♪
♪来 把手给我♪
♪ Komm, gib Mir deine Hand ♪
-希特勒万岁 约克  -希特勒万岁 乔乔
- Heil Hitler, Yorki. - Heil Hitler, Jojo.
你准备好迎接最棒的周末了吗
Are you ready for the best weekend ever?
-是的 我准备好了  -出发吧
- Yes, I am! - Let's go!
从来没有和别人在一起过
♪ Das war noch nie bei einer Anderen ♪
♪曾经如此♪
♪ Einmal so ♪
♪噢 你真漂亮♪
♪ Oh, Du bist so schön ♪
像♪钻石一样♪
♪ Schön wie ein Diamant ♪
♪一起去♪
♪ Ich will mit Dir gehen ♪
♪来 把手给我♪
♪ Komm, gib Mir deine Hand ♪
-希特勒万岁 各位  -希特勒万岁
- Heil Hitler, guys. - Heil Hitler!
青年团们 欢迎来到希特勒青年训练周末
Jungvolk, welcome to the Hitlerjugend training weekend.
我们会在这里把你们培养成真正的大人
In which we will make men and women of you all.
我是克伦森多队长
My name is Captain Klenzendorf.
-你们可以叫我K队长  -K队长
- You may call me Captain K. - Captain K!
这位是芬克尔副官
And this is Sub-Officer Finkel.
这位是拉姆小姐
This is Fräulein Rahm.
大家好 希特勒万岁
Hey, Heil Hitler, everyone.
那么关于我的问题 我是谁 我为什么在这里
So, a little about me. Who am I and why am I here,
和一群小鬼聊天
talking to a bunch of little titty-grabbers,
而不是带领我的战士们战死沙场 问得好
instead of leading my men into battle to their glorious deaths. Great question.
搞砸行动后我每天都在问自己
I've been asking myself every day since operation "Screw up".
在一次防守敌人进攻的时候 我弄瞎了一只眼睛
Where I lost a perfectly good eye in a totally preventable enemy attack.
但我上级说 要双眼健全的人才能在战场上有所贡献
And according to my superiors, you need two eyes to be a meaningful part of the war effort.
双眼健全的人有我枪法准吗
Can two eyed people do this?
天呐
Jesus!
在接下来的两天里 你们这些小家伙将体验到
Over the next two days, you, little critters, will get to experience
我的部队老师每天都要经历的一些事情
some of the things that my teacher in the army goes through every day.
即使我们的国家看起来很落后
And even though it would appear our country is on a back foot,
而且赢得这场战争的希望也不大
and there really isn't much hope in that's winning this war.
但显然 我们目前状况还不错
Apparently, we're doing just fine.
无论如何
Anyway.
你们每个人都配发了德军的刺刀
You boys have all been issued with your Deutsches Jungvolk Daggers.
这些都是材质特殊 造价昂贵的武器
These are very special and expensive weapons.
你们不准把它弄丢 也不准刺伤彼此
You should never be without them. And don't try to stab each other!
不许刺人
No stabbing!
No stabbing.
这是你们成为男子汉的第一步
This is your first step towards being men.
今天你们的训练内容有
Today you boys will be involved in such activities, as
行军 刺刀演习 扔手榴弹 挖壕沟 判读地图 防毒
marching, bayonet drills, grenade throwing, trench digging, map reading, gas defense,
伪装 伏击技术 战争游戏 射击和爆破
camouflage, ambush techniques, war games, firing guns and blowing stuff up.
女孩们将训练重要的女性职责 比如
The girls will practice important womanly duties, such as
包扎伤口 铺床 学习如何生孩子
dressing wounds, making beds, and learning how to get pregnant.
我为德国生了18个孩子
I've had 18 kids for Germany.
这年头做女孩真好
Such a great year to be a girl.
好吧 我们开始吧
All right. Let's get to it.
上帝保佑
God help me.
♪当我晚上躺在床上♪
♪ When I'm lyin' in my bed at night ♪
♪我不想长大♪
♪ I don't wanna grow up ♪
♪似乎没有什么是对的♪
♪ Nothin' ever seems to turn out right ♪
♪我不想长大♪
♪ I don't wanna grow up ♪
三 二 一 纳粹党
Three, two, one - swastika.
♪总是改变着事情♪
♪ That's always changing things ♪
♪让我希望我能成为一只狗♪
♪ Makes me wish that I could be a dog ♪
♪当我看到你支付的价格♪
♪ When I see the price that you pay ♪
♪我不想长大♪
♪ I don't wanna grow up ♪
♪我不想那样♪
♪ I don't ever wanna be that way ♪
♪我不想长大♪
♪ I don't wanna grow up ♪
-现在干掉他  -不要 不要
- Now, finish him. - Don't, don't!
♪唯一能活到今天♪
♪ The only thing to live for is today... ♪
-獠牙  -獠牙 是的
- Fangs. - Fangs, ja.
-毒蛇舌头  -毒蛇舌头 好
- Serpent tongue. - Serpent tongue, ja.
-鱼鳞  -对 鱼鳞
- Scales. - Ja, scales.
因为曾经有个犹太人和一条鱼交配
Because once upon a time a Jewish man mated with a fish.
雅利安种族比其他种族文明先进1000倍
The Aryans are 1000 times more civilized and advanced than any other race.
现在 把你们的东西收拾好 孩子们 是时候烧一些书了
Now, get your things together, kids, it's time to burn some books.
♪梳头擦鞋♪
♪ Comb their hair and shine their shoes ♪
♪我不想长大♪
♪ I don't wanna grow up ♪
♪徘徊的我的家乡♪
♪ Stay around in my old hometown ♪
♪我不想付定金♪
♪ I don't wanna put no money down ♪
♪不想借我一大笔旧债♪
♪ I don't wanna get me a big old loan ♪
♪把手指伸到骨头那里♪
♪ Work them fingers to the bone ♪
♪不想让扫帚飘起来♪
♪ I don't wanna float a broom ♪
♪坠入爱河然后结婚生子♪
♪ Fall in love and get married then boom ♪
♪进展为何如此迅速♪
♪ How the hell did it get here so soon ♪
♪我不想长大♪
♪ I don't wanna grow up ♪
犹太人听起来很吓人 不是吗
Jews sound scary, huh?
我不觉得
Not to me.
如果我遇到了 我会像这样杀了他
If I met one, I'd kill it like that.
就像
Like...
这样
That.
但你怎么知道他是不是犹太人  他们能伪装成我们的样子
But how would you know if you saw one? They can look just like us.
我会确认他头上有没有犄角
I’d feel its head for horns.
他们闻起来就像芽甘蓝
And they smell like Brussels sprouts.
噢是的 我都忘了芽甘蓝这个特征
Oh yeah, I forgot about the Brussels sprouts bit.
要是能抓个犹太人给希特勒
Imagine catching one and giving it to Hitler.
那肯定能让我成为他私人保镖的一员
That’d be a sure-fire way to get into his personal guards.
然后我们就会成为最好的朋友
Then, we would become best friends.
我以为我是你最好的朋友
I thought I was your best friend.
约克 你是我第二好的朋友
Yorki, you’re my 2nd best friend.
第一好友是留给元首的
First place is reserved for the Führer.
除非你是希特勒 藏在一个小胖子身体里
So, unless you’re Hitler, hiding in a fat little boy’s body,
这样我和第二好友在一起也开心
I’d be happy with 2nd place.
我觉得我只是一个身材肥胖的小屁孩
I guess I'm just a kid in a fat kid's body.
谈话结束
Case closed.
当你们站在敌人面前 不得不杀了他时
When you stand before the enemy, and have to end his life.
你们谁有勇气这么做
which of you will have the stomach to do this?
很好
Good.
希特勒的军队不需要懦夫
There is no room in Hitler's army for those that lack strength.
我们只需要坚毅的勇士
We want hardened warriors.
随时做好杀戮的准备
Those, that are prepared to kill at will.
-你们能做到吗  -能
- Can you do this? - Yes.
乔纳斯
Johannes.
你能杀人吗
Can you kill?
当然能 我喜欢杀戮
Pff, of course. I love killing.
很好
Good.
过来
Come here.
别害怕 来吧
Don't be scared. Come on.
很好
Good.
杀了这只兔子
Kill it.
拧断它的脖子 杀了这只兔子
Wring its neck and kill the rabbit.
还是你害怕
Or are you scared?
我没有害怕
I'm not scared.
我只是
I just...
杀了它
Now!
双手放在它脖子上
Place both hands around its neck,
一只手用力拧
and then one hard twist.
兔子可能会惨叫 但我们会用脚踩死它
He might scream, but we’ll just use the boot to finish it off.
杀了它
Kill!
干的漂亮
Good shot.
你和你父亲一样 都是懦夫
You are a coward. Just like your father.
他不是懦夫 他在意大利打仗呢
He’s not a coward, he’s fighting in Italy.
是吗 已经两年了 他杳无音信
Really? Well, no one has heard from him in 2 years.
他是个懦弱的逃兵
He is a deserting coward.
他害怕 你也一样
He's scared, and so are you.
你就像只胆小的兔子
You're as scared as a little rabbit.
胆小兔 也许我们也应该拧断你的脖子
Scared little rabbit. Maybe we should snap your neck too?
乔乔兔
Jojo the rabbit.
Jojo Rabbit.
可怜的乔乔 怎么了 小子
Poor Jojo. What's wrong, little man?
嗨 阿道夫
Hi, Adolf.
要不要告诉我关于兔子的事 都发生了什么
Wanna tell me about that rabbit incident? What was all that about?
他们想要我杀了那只兔子
They wanted me to kill it.
我很抱歉 我不敢
I'm sorry. I couldn't.
别担心 我不在意这些
Don't worry about it. I couldn't care less.
但是现在他们都叫我胆小兔
But now they call me a scared rabbit.
那些人想说什么就让他们说吧 之前也有人说我很多坏话
Let them say whatever they want. People used to say a lot of nasty things about me.
这家伙是个疯子 看那个神经病 他可能会害死我们
This guy is a lunatic. Look at that psycho, he's gonna get us all killed.
告诉你个秘密
I'll let you in on a little secret.
兔子不是懦夫
The rabbit is no coward.
这温顺的小家伙每天都面对这个危险的世界
The humble little bunny faces the dangerous world every day,
为它的家人 族群 搜寻萝卜
hunting carrots for his family, for his country.
我的领域充满了敌人
My empire would be full of all animals.
狮子 长颈鹿 斑马 犀牛 章鱼
Lions, giraffes, zebras, rhinoceroses, octopuses,
犀牛章
Rhinoctopuses.
甚至勇猛的兔子
Even the mighty rabbit.
来支烟
Cigarette?
不了谢谢  我不抽烟
No thanks, I don't smoke.
给你出个好主意
Let me give you some really good advice.
当只兔子
Be the rabbit.
温顺的兔子可以瞒骗所有的敌人
The humble bunny can outwit all of his enemies.
他很勇敢 狡猾且强壮
He's brave and sneaky and strong.
当只兔子吧
Be the rabbit.
乔乔
Jojo.
你没事吧 乔乔
Are you all right, Jojo?
你刚和谁说话
Who were you talking to?
没谁
Nobody.
我还以为你在哭呢
I thought you were crying.
你是眼泪方面的专家吗
Are you a tear-job specialist?
不是
No.
谈话结束
Case closed.
现在 轮到乔乔
Now, it's time for Jojo
让那些呆虫知道
to show those stick insects
谁才是真正的胆小兔
who is the real cowardly rabbit.
抱歉 你在说什么呢
I'm sorry, what are you talking about?
没什么
Never mind.
乔乔 你要去哪儿
Jojo, where are you going?
去当兔子
To be the rabbit!
乔乔兔
Jojo Rabbit!
猎食胡萝卜 乔乔兔
Hunting carrots, Jojo Rabbit!
嘿 这太棒了 我们就像两只羚羊人
Hey, this is amazing! We're like two human antelopes.
现在 孩子们
Now, lads.
你们每个人轮流点燃并投掷一颗手榴弹
Each of you will be given the opportunity to ignite and throw a grenade.
我会亲自指导你们每一个人
I will personally be supervising each of you
确保你们不会炸掉你们的眼睛之类的
to make sure you don't blow your eyes out, or something.
好的 谁先来
All right. Who's first?
克劳斯
Klaus!
该死
Shit!
别学他
Don't do that.
乔乔
Jojo!
芬克尔 抬他上车
Feldscher, take him in.
乔乔
Jojo!
噢天呐  他看起来就像毕加索的画
Oh mein Gott, he looks like a Picasso painting.
他妈妈会杀了我的
His mother is going to kill me.
我的小可爱
My darling cub.
嘿 孩子
Hey, kid.
我的小可爱
My darling little cub.
你为什么这么高兴 你儿子丑的像个怪物
Why so happy? Your son is ugly like a monster.
嘿 你不是怪物
Hey, you're no monster!
而且你的伤疤会愈合 腿也会恢复的
Besides, your scars will heal and you'll get most of the movement back in your legs.
但我永远不能成为希特勒的私人保镖了
But I'll never be in Hitler's personal guards.
你会没事的
You're fine as you are.
我很开心你能回家
I'm just happy to have you back home.
狮妈妈很担心她的幼崽  尤其是狮爸爸不在的时候
Mama lion worries about her cub, especially when papa lion isn't here.
或狮姐姐英加
Or Inga lion.
抓住兔子的尾巴  绑上兔子的耳朵
Grab the rabbit by the tail, wrap it around his ear.
用力绑紧 然后扔回洞中
Tie it all up and then stuff him back down the hole.
现在 我们出发吧
Now then, let's get on our way.
我觉得出门走走有助于你的康复
I think getting out of the house will do wonders for your recuperation.
我不想出门
I don't want to go out there.
什么 别傻了 你当然要出门
What? Don't be silly. Of course, you do.
我看起来很蠢
I look stupid.
人们会盯着我看的
People will stare.
那就享受人们的关注 孩子
Enjoy the attention, kid.
不是每个人都那么幸运能看起来很蠢的
Not everyone is lucky enough to look stupid.
比如说我 就只能天生丽质难自弃
I, for one, am cursed to look incredibly attractive.
现在 你需要鼓起勇气
Now, you're going to pluck up your courage,
走出家门 开启一场奇妙冒险
walk out that door and have an incredible adventure.
好吗
Okay?
好吧
Okay.
菲尔德·马歇尔·乔乔 你是我们家最棒的男人
Field Marshall Jojo, you’re our top man.
准备好离开家门
Prepare to leave the house.
外面危险吗
Is it dangerous?
极其危险
Extremely.
希特勒万岁
Heil Hitler!
上帝啊
Jesus!
看起来不错 孩子
Looking good, kid.
贝茨勒夫人 你看起来和往常一样迷人
Frau Betzler, you're looking fetching, as usual.
都是因为你 害的我儿子不能正常走路 还毁了容
It's because of you my son can't walk properly and has a messed up face.
他抢了我的手榴弹 就扔…
He stole my hand grenade, just took...
对 对…
Yeah, yeah...
所以 在我工作的时候替我好好照顾他
So, you are going to look after him while I'm at work.
确保他有事做 不受排挤 知道了吗
Make sure he has a job and feels included, got it?
知道了 是 我知道了
Got it. Yeah, I really got it.
很好
Good.
各位 这是乔纳斯·贝茨勒 我和你们说过这孩子 还记得吗
Guys, this is Johannes Betzler, a kid I told you about, remember?
他抢了手榴弹 把自己炸飞了 最后我因为疏忽大意被降职了
He stole the hand grenade and blew himself up, and as a result I got demoted for negligence.
现在我只能和这些可爱的孩子一起在办公室工作
Now I get to work in this office with all these wonderful kids.
那么乔乔 我们会给你找一些活做
So, Jojo, I'm sure we can figure out something for you to do.
各位有什么提议吗
Ideas? Guys?
是的 我们需要人来陪这些克隆人
okay, we need somebody to walk the clones.
或者 他也可以去发这些新传单
Also, I think, maybe he could hand out this new propaganda,
贴征兵的广告
and deliver these conscriptions.
我想去应征入伍 可以吗
I don't suppose I could be conscripted, could I?
是的 这是个好主意
Yes, that's a wonderful idea.
我全权授权 允许你们把这个十岁的男孩送去战场
Yes, I give my full permission for you to send this 10 year old child into war.
有人能给他支枪吗
Will someone get this kid a gun?
我很乐意去法国打仗
And I'll be more than happy to fight in the France.
排队等着吧  孩子
Get in line, kid.
好的 这是征兵广告
Okay, here's the conscriptions.
这是你的枪
And here's the gun.
不用
No.
呸
Yuck!
看着
Look.
他们做了什么事
What did they do?
做了他们能做的
What they could.
走吧
Come on.
嘿 乔乔兔 看看你的怂样
Hey, Jojo Rabbit! Look at your face.
我要上战场了 你这个胆小鬼
I'm going to war, and you are a pup man!
乔乔兔
Jojo Rabbit!
妈妈
Mama?
菲尔德·马歇尔·乔乔回来了
Field Marshall Jojo is home.
你在家吗
Mama?
妈妈 我回来了
Mama, I'm home.
妈妈
Mama?
嗨
Hi.
你想干什么
What do you want?
你是鬼吗
Are you a ghost?
是的 我是鬼
Sure. A ghost.
别逼我追你 小鬼
Don't make me run, kid!
我很久没吃东西了 你知道我们特别喜欢鲜血的滋味
I'm far too hungry, and you know how much we love the taste of blood.
丢东西了吗
Lost something?
告诉你乔纳斯 我不是鬼 但我比鬼更可怕
I'm not a ghost Johannes, I'm something worse,
我想你已经猜到了 是吗？
but I think you already know that, don't you?
你知道我是什么人
You know what I am?
-不知道  -你知道
- No. - Yes.
说
Say it.
快说
Say it!
犹太人
A Jew.
祝你健康
Gesundheit.
你不能呆在这
You can't be here.
是吗 你妈妈邀请我的 所以我算是她的客人
Well, your mother invited me, so, I suppose, that makes me her guest.
不可以
Not allowed!
那你想怎样呢 亲爱的小希特勒？
What will you do sweet Hitlerchen?
好啊
Of course.
去吧 告诉他们
Go on then. Tell them.
但是你知道这样做的后果吗
But you know what happens if you do?
我会告诉他们是你和你母亲帮的我
I'll tell them you helped me. And your mother too.
然后我们一起完蛋
And we'll all be kaput.
如果你告诉她你见过我
And if you tell her you know about me.
敢说一个字
Just one word.
我会极其乐意把你那纳粹脑袋砍下来
I'll do the world a great big favor and cut your Nazi head off.
听懂了吗
Got it?
懂了
Yeah.
这把刀我收下了
I think I'll hold on to this.
很好看
It's pretty.
天哪 刚才真惊险
Sheesh, that was intense.
我该怎么办
What am I going to do?
说实话 不知道
Honestly, no idea.
我是说 犹太人可能比我们想象的更多 你家墙后就可能住着几百个
I mean, there could be more of them. Hundreds of them, living in your walls.
她是怎么办到的
How did she get control like that?
她肯定用了精神控制术
She must've used her powers. Mind control.
绝对是
Typical.
-你看见她刚跑得有多快吗  -看到了
- You saw how fast she moved? - Yes.
就像少女版犹太人杰斯·欧文斯
Like a little female Jewish Jesse Owens.
她还抢走了你漂亮的小刀
And now she's got your fancy knife.
我的刀
A knife!
是的 就像少女版版犹太人杰斯·欧文斯·开膛手杰克
Yeah, like a little female Jewish Jesse Owens Jack the Ripper.
你现在真的处境不妙啊 我的朋友
You're definitely in a pickle, my friend.
如何是好
What to do?
有啦
Got it!
把房子烧了 然后说是温斯顿·丘吉尔干的
Burn down the house and blame Winston Churchill.
要不就谈判
Or negotiate.
打扰一下
Excuse me?
小女孩
Little girl?
墙里的犹太女孩
Jew girl in the wall?
哟嚯 犹太人
Yoohoo, Jew?
好吧 那我就直说了 就是
Okay, well, I’ll just say what I have to say, and that's this,
我不怕你 而且我认为
I'm not scared of you and I think
你应该找别的地方去住 好吗
you should find somewhere else to live, okay?
不好
Not okay.
滚出我的房间
Get, the hell, out of my room.
你看 她真野蛮
She's pretty rude, you know.
刚才那只是我的两枚硬币
That’s just my 2 pfennige.
现在她可有两把刀了
And now she's got two knives.
我知道
I know!
这下你用什么切东西
How are you gonna chop up stuff?
我不知道
I don't know!
而且她还没走 还有 就是...
And she's still up there too, that thing, that...
-她是犹太人  -没错 犹太人
- Jew! - Yeah, Jew, yeah.
我们该拿那个犹太人怎么办呢
What are we gonna do about that Jew?
你来想办法
You think of something.
现在我成专家了
Now I'm the expert?
别再给我递烟了 真讨厌 我才十岁
Stop offering me, damn, cigarettes! I'm ten!
好 对不起 我这会压力太大
Okay, sorry, I'm stressed out.
好 现在我们像土耳其人一样谈谈
Okay, let's talk like turkeys.
你不能告诉你母亲这件事 不然犹太人会砍下你的脑袋
You can't tell your mother or that Jew will cut off your Nazi head.
但是 阁楼里的这件事没理由毁了你的生活
But, there's no reason this thing in the attic needs to ruin your life.
事实上 你还可以利用她
In fact, you could use her to your advantage.
怎么说
How?
当有人试图控制我的心智时
When someone tries to use mind powers on me.
你知道我怎么做吗 反过来控制他们的
You know what I do? Use mind powers back on them.
还记得去年的时候 那个独臂海盗
Remember last year, when that one-armed pirate
冯·斯塔芬伯格想用桌上的炸弹炸死我吗
Von Stauffenberg tried to blow me up with a table bomb?
-记得 你活下了来  -回答正确
- Yeah, you survived. - Correct-a-mundo.
但除了我的腿不怕炸弹外 我能活下来的唯一原因
But the only reason I survived, apart from having bomb-proof legs,
就是我智取了老冯·斯塔夫
is because I outwitted old Von Stauffy.
我让他以为我死了 但其实我还活得好好的
I let him think that I was dead, when in actual fact I was absolutely fine.
凭借假死 我揪出了所有的背叛者
By pretending I was dead I drew out all the traitors.
所以你该怎么做
So, what are you going to do?
-我也假装死了  -没错
- Pretend I'm dead? - Exactly.
等一下 不是
Wait, no.
不 我是这个意思
No, what I mean is this.
你让她感到安全 她就会放松警惕 这样你就能夺取控制权
Make her feel safe, and then she'll drop her guard and then you will be the one in control.
反向心理学
Reverse psychology.
不要把事情复杂化
Don't complicate things.
就用我的逆向思维能力技巧 一切都会水到渠成
Just use my backwards mind power trick, and everything will be fine.
我要走了 我家今天的晚餐是独角兽哦
I gotta go. We are having a unicorn for dinner at my place tonight.
集中精神 乔乔
Concentrate, Jojo.
记住 一个住在你墙后的犹太人总比
Remember, a Jew living in your wall is better than
两个像蝙蝠一样从烟囱飞进来吃无辜纳粹的犹太人要好
two Jews flying around with their bat wings, climbing down chimneys and eating innocent Nazis.
还有再别给她送刀了
And don't give her anymore knives!
我去也
Jews.
我的童子军 你怎么起来了
Darling cub, why are you up?
吃晚饭了吗
Did you eat anything?
对不起 我忘记时间了 我走了很久 边走边想...
Sorry, I lost track of time, I was talking a long walk and having a think...
你怎么不把鞋带绑好呢
What are we going to do with these laces?
我的天 你知道你该把鞋带绑好的
My goodness, you know, you'll have to tie them, eventually, you know.
-我听到她的声音了  -什么
- I heard her. - What?
你说谁
Who?
英加 她的鬼魂
Inga. Her ghost.
我真替你难过
It's so sad for you.
你都神志不清了
You've lost your mind.
但我更可怜 因为我得和一个傻孩子住在一起
It's sadder for me though, because I have to live with a crazy person.
我听到楼上有声音
I heard noises upstairs.
鬼魂 认真的吗
Ghosts, honestly?
你知道我听到什么了吗 老鼠
You know what I heard? Rats.
是的 我们家里有老鼠 你敢相信吗
Yes, we have them. Can you believe that?
它们很脏 我一直劝你最好你不要去楼上
Dirty animals, I've been meaning to tell you to stay away from upstairs
直到我把它们全部清理掉 好吗 我不想让你染上病菌
until I've cleared them all, okay? I don't need you getting sick.
好的 妈妈
Okay, Mama.
我会小心那些肮脏的老鼠的
I'll watch out for those dirty rats.
刀怎么都不见了
Where are all, the goddamn, knives?
你也准备去睡觉吗
Are you going to bed too?
是 我一会就睡 我得先去整理些东西
Yes, soon. I have to tidy some things first.
什么东西
What things?
妈妈的东西
Mama things.
孩子 你得相信我 好吗 我是这儿的一家之主 不是吗？
Boy, you have to trust me, okay? I'm the boss here, yeah?
我猜是
I guess.
好孩子
Good boy.
对 但是有一只眼睛得睁开
Yes, but with one eye.
差不多了
Almost.
不是很对
Not quite.
太棒了 你做到了 耶
Great! You got it. Yeah.
你动静得再小点 他听到楼上的声音了
You have to be more quiet, he heard noises up here.
如果我得在你和我儿子之间做选择 我...
If I have to choose between you and my son, I...
我不知道把你送去哪里 你明白了吗
I won't know where to send you. You hear me?
不能让他知道 如果他知道了那他们就都知道了
He can't know. If he knows then they know.
你可以和他讲道理
You could reason with him.
你不了解他 他是个极端分子
You don't know him. He's a fanatic.
他花了三个星期才忘记他祖父不是金发碧眼的事实
It took him 3 weeks to get over the fact that his grandfather was not blond.
我知道他还保留着以前的天性
I know he's in there somewhere.
那个孩子喜欢玩耍却又害怕天黑 所以会奔向你
The little boy, who loves to play, and runs to you because he's scared of sundown.
还天真地以为是你发明的巧克力蛋糕
And thinks you invented the chocolate cake.
不过到头来也只是心里
In the end it's only a way of
留有希望
hope,
不愿自己仅剩的孩子沦为另一个鬼魂
in that your only remaining child is not just another ghost.
也许我们现在都是鬼魂了 只是不知道而已
Perhaps we all ghosts now, and we just don't know it.
也许吧
Perhaps.
你比大多数人活得更久
You've lived more lifetimes than most.
我那根本就不叫活着
I haven't lived at all.
你被改变了
You're being changed.
他们都说你活不了
And they say you can't live, that you won't live.
如果你真死了 那他们就赢了
If that comes true, then they win.
但目前他们一直是赢家
They have been winning so far.
他们不会赢的 你有着不可战胜的力量
They'll never win, that's the power you have.
无论何处 只要还有幸存者 他们就会输
As long as there's someone alive, somewhere, then they lose.
他们昨天和今天都没发现你 你要确保明天也不会
They didn't get you yesterday or today, you make tomorrow the same.
嘿
Hey.
明天也一样要躲好
Tomorrow must be the same.
天呐 痛死啦
Jesus Christ!
你必须做拉伸 那很痛吗
You must stretch. Does that hurt you?
超级痛
Yes.
很好 疼痛是你的朋友
Good. Pain is your friend.
很快你的腿就能恢复的只有一点点变形
Soon your leg will only be a little bit deformed and pointless.
我要把你推荐到其他游泳池去
I'm going to recommend another month of pool,
因为你脸上的伤可能会吓到其他孩子
because your face might scare the other kids.
很难看
It's kind of ugly.
好了 下一位该谁
Okay, who's next?
乔乔 我得走了
Jojo, baby, I have to go.
家里见
See you at home.
你好 K队长
Hi, Captain K.
嘿 这不是把手榴弹扔向自己的小家伙吗
Hey, if it isn't the hand grenade himself.
腿怎么样了 孩子
How's the leg, kid?
痊愈得差不多了 已经没之前那么痛了
It's pretty much healed. It only 80 % hurts now.
你们在这儿干什么呢
What are you guys doing?
我来教部队男孩们进行水战训练的
I'm here to teach the HG boys water warfare training.
你知道的 以防他们有一天要在泳池里打战
You know, in case they ever need to go to battle in the swimming pool.
我能问你个关于犹太人的问题吗
Can I ask you a question about Jews?
哦 什么问题
Oh God, why?
要是我发现个犹太人 我该怎么做
What should I do if I see one?
这样 如果你发现了犹太人 你告诉我们 我们再告诉盖世太保
Okay, if you see a Jew, you tell us, we tell the Gestapo,
他们再去告诉党卫军 然后军人会去杀了那个犹太人
and they tell the SS, and then they go, and they kill the Jew.
也会杀掉帮助过犹太人的人
And anyone who helped the Jew.
因为现在处于多疑时期 宁可错杀一千 也不放过一个
And, because, these are very paranoid times, probably some other people just in case.
这也是联合军队的过程
It's a pretty joined up process.
即使是犹太人先利用催眠让某人帮他们藏身也不放过吗
Even if the Jew hypnotized someone to make them hide the Jew in the first place?
我不太相信会有这种事发生
I'd be amazed if that could happen.
不 这事有可能发生
No, it can happen.
我叔叔就遇到过
It happened to my uncle.
有个犹太人催眠了他 把他变得嗜酒如命
A Jew hypnotized him, and he became a massive drunk,
好赌成性 还拈花惹草
and a gambler, and he cheated on his wife,
甚至跟我妹妹有着暧昧之情
and he had an inappropriate relationship with my sister,
他最后在一场无关的事故中一命呜呼
and then he drowned in an unrelated accident.
这都归咎于犹太人
But it was the Jew's fault.
不管怎样 你看到犹太人了吗
Anyway, did you see one? A Jew?
就算看到我也不确定能否分辨出来
I'm not sure I'd be able to tell if I did.
我也不能 没有他们滑稽的帽子 要认出来简直不可能
Me neither. Without their funny hats it’s damn near impossible.
应该有人写本如何分辨犹太人的书
Someone should write a book on the subject.
那样事情就简单多了
That would make things so much easier.
芬克尔 他们溺水了 快去救人
Finky, they are drowning, come on.
回头见 小家伙
I'll see you later, little man.
好吧 现在情况是这样的
Okay, here's the situation.
如果我告发你 你就会有大麻烦
If I tell on you, you'll be in big trouble.
我想你不希望那样
And I don't think you want that.
但你会接着告发我和我母亲 我们就会有大麻烦
But then you'll tell on me and my mother, and we'll be in trouble,
这是我不希望的
which I don't want.
如果你告诉母亲我知道你的存在 她就会赶你出去
And if you tell my mother I know, then she'll kick you out,
这是你不希望的
which you don't want.
如果我去告诉母亲我知道这件事 你就会砍掉我的脑袋
And if I tell my mother I know, then you'll cut off my Nazi head,
这又是我不希望的
which I also don't want.
所以现在陷入双方都不利的僵局
So, it's a Mexican stalemate.
这只是个普通的僵局
It's just a normal stalemate.
你想留在这里就得答应我一些条件
I have some conditions for allowing you to stay here.
-条件  -没错
- Conditions? - Yes.
你要告诉我关于犹太人的一切
Tell me everything about the Jewish race.
没问题
Okay.
我们和你们外貌一样 但我们有人性
We are like you, but human.
请你认真一点
Please take this seriously.
你就当这是一次曝光 我想知道你们所有的秘密
Think of this as an exposé. I want to know all your secrets.
请你不要坐在我姐姐的床上
Kindly refrain from sitting on my sister's bed!
小子 她用不上这床
Boy, she doesn't need it.
你对我姐姐一无所知
You know nothing of my sister.
我和英加曾经是好朋友
Inga and I were friends.
我记得你 多么有趣的小男孩啊
I remember you. Such a funny little boy.
废话少说 开始跟我讲讲你们的种族
Enough with the small talk. Start telling me about your kind.
显然 我们都是贪财的恶魔 对吗
Obviously, we are demons, who love money, right?
当然了 众所周知的事
Obviously, everyone knows that.
但人们不知道的是 我们还对食物过敏
But what people don't know is that we also allergic to food.
像奶酪 面包 肉这些 这些东西会立马要了我们的命
Cheese, bread, meat. That stuff will kill us instantly.
所以你如果想了结我的性命 这是最快的方法
So, if you are thinking of ending my life, that's the fastest way.
还有饼干 也是致命的
Also biscuits - lethal.
真好笑
Very funny.
反正食物不够你吃 所以我不知道你到底想干嘛
Anyway, there's not enough food for you, so I don't know what are you doing to do.
你母亲设法给我找了些面包
Your mother managed to find me some bread.
她很善良 把我当人看待
She's kind. She treats me like a person.
但你不是人 不是个正派的人
But you're not. Not a proper person.
那你是吗
Are you?
你竟敢出言不逊 犹太人
How dare you, Jew?
你像根睫毛一样弱不禁风
You are weak, like an eyelash.
我有纯正的雅利安血统 血液如玫瑰那般鲜红
I am born of Aryan ancestry. My blood is the color of a pure red rose.
我的眼睛是蓝色的
And my eyes are blue.
挣脱啊
Break free.
伟大的雅利安人有本事就挣脱 犹太人没有软弱的
Break free great Aryan. There are no weak Jews.
我是那些敢与天使搏斗 敢杀巨人的强者的后代
I am descended from those, who wrestle angels and kill giants.
我们是被上帝选中的种族
We were chosen by God.
你不过是被一个连胡子都长不齐的可怜虫选中
You were chosen by pathetic little man, who can't even grow a full mustache.
还好意思说是更强的种族
The stronger race, huh?
所以你跟楼上那个犹太人的事进展如何
So, how is it all going with that Jew thing upstairs?
她根本不想和我说话
Well, she doesn't want to talk to me.
因为你是个纳粹分子
Well, you are a Nazi.
我想也是
I guess.
这本关于犹太人的书比我预想的要难写的多
This book is going to be harder to write than I though.
她在干嘛 她在烧东西
What's she doing? She's burning something.
烧的什么啊 你在烧什么东西
What is she burning? What are you burning?
她听不见你问
She can't hear you.
你在烧什么呢
What are you burning?
为什么这么开心
Why so happy?
事情正在转变
Things are changing.
同盟国拿下了意大利 接下来是法国 很快战争就要结束了
The allies have taken Italy, France will be next. And soon the war will be over.
该死的
God dammit!
你为什么这么高兴 你就这么恨自己的国家吗
Why does that make you happy? You hate your country that much?
我爱我的国家 我恨的是战争 这些战争既无意义又愚蠢至极
I love my country, it's the war I hate. It's pointless and stupid,
所以和平来的越早越好
and the sooner we have peace the better.
噢 战争迟早会结束 我们会将敌人挫骨扬灰
Oh, the war will end. We will crash our enemies into dust!
当他们被毁灭时 我们会把他们的坟墓当做……
And when they are destroyed, we shall use their graves as...
够了 别谈政治了
Okay, no more politics.
晚餐是中立地带 这张饭桌就代表瑞士
Dinner is neutral ground. This table is Switzerland.
我们吃饭吧
Let's eat.
你没在吃东西
You aren't eating.
没 我还没那么饿 可能会晚点再吃
No, I am not that hungry. I might eat later.
我现在就想喝一些葡萄酒
For now, I'm just going to chew on these grapes.
我今晚倒是特别饿 所以我可能会把你那份也吃掉
Well, I'm especially hungry tonight, so, maybe, I'll just finish yours.
不想浪费粮食
Don't want it to go to waste.
你今天过得怎样 乔纳斯
How was your day Johannes?
你知道的 就四处闲逛 当一个没有生活目标的畸形儿童
Oh, you know, just wandered around, being a deformed kid who has nothing to live for.
你才没有畸形
You are not deformed.
我的脸花的就像街道地图一样惨不忍睹
My face looks like a, goddamn, street map, woman.
我不指望你能理解 如果我父亲在这儿 他肯定能理解
I wouldn't expect you to understand. If my father was here, he'd get it.
可是他不在
Well, he's not.
我知道 不仅如此 我还无法摆脱你
I know. And instead, I'm stuck with you.
-你想要你父亲是吧  -是的 没错
- You want your Daddy? - Yeah, I do.
是吗
Yeah.
那好
Fine!
不准跟你母亲那样讲话
Don't you ever talk to your, goddamn, mother like that!
保罗 怎么了
Paul, what happened?
保罗
Paul?
我冲孩子发火了
I yelled at the kid.
什么 快去道歉
What? Go apologize.
对不起 孩子
Sorry, kid.
啥 你那算哪门子道歉
What? What kind of apology was that?
对不起 孩子
Sorry, kid.
乔乔
Jojo.
我知道你很想我 但是我
I know you miss me, but I'm..
我去了别的地方 努力想让这世界变得不同
I'm out there, trying to make a difference in the world.
在我离开的这段时间里 拜托你照顾好我的萝丝
And while I'm gone, I need you to take care of my Rosie.
你能做到吗
Can you do that?
我能做到 爸爸
Yes, Dad.
谢谢
Thanks.
她也在尽她所能了
She's doing what she can.
哦 上帝 我们有个好孩子 不是吗
Oh, Gosh. We made a good kid, huh?
是的 好极了
Damn, that's good!
让我想起我和萝丝在红色沙龙跳舞的场景
It reminds me of dancing with Rosie in the red salon.
亲爱的 你还记得吗
You remember, honey?
宝贝 我当然记得
Of course, I do, babe.
嘿
Hey.
孩子 别一直坐着 来和爸爸妈妈跳舞
Don't just sit there, kid. Come, dance with your parents.
我想你帮我画幅画 内容包括犹太人住的地方
So, I'd like you to draw a picture of where Jews live.
吃饭睡觉以及犹太主妇放鸡蛋的地方
Where you all eat, sleep, and where the Queen Jew lays the eggs.
你真是个蠢货
You really are an idiot.
快点 我们还有很多事要做
Come on, we have a lot of work to do.
和我说说你家里的情况吧
Tell me about your family.
我可以告诉你犹太人的情况 但你没有权利知道我家庭的情况
I'll tell you about the Jews, but you are not privileged to know about my family.
但我得了解你的背景
But I need background.
你怎么总粘着我 你没有其他朋友吗
Why are you hanging around with me, don't you have any friends?
当然有了 他叫约克
Of course! Yorki.
-约克  -我最好的朋友
- Yorki? - Amongst others.
-你没有好朋友吧  -我有 他叫内森
- You don't have anyone. - I have Nathan.
内森 这家伙是谁
Nathan? Who, the hell, is that?
我的未婚夫 他是我最好的朋友
My fiancée. I have him.
他在哪
Where is he?
他在打仗 你看
Fighting in the resistance. See?
他曾在河边向我求婚
He proposed to me on the banks of the Fluss.
他朗诵着里尔克的诗 像位绅士般单膝跪地向我求婚
He knelt down like a proper gentleman, recited a poem by Rilke.
我回答'我愿意'之后 我们就在夜色中翩翩起舞
And when I said yes we danced into the night.
真无聊 谁是里尔克
Snore. Who’s Rilke?
一位伟大的诗人 内森最爱的诗人
A great poet. Nathan's favorite.
哦 内森最爱的诗人 知道了
Oh, Nathan's favorite? Yeah.
他会来救我出去 然后我们要去巴黎生活
He's coming to rescue me, and then we'll go live in Paris.
你想永远背弃德国吗
You'd turn your back on Germany forever?
是它先抛弃我的
It turned on me first.
好吧 我们不需要你这种人
Well, we don't need you.
你和你的蠢男友闭嘴吧 你们就去那个
You and your stupid boyfriend can shut up and go live in
人人沉默寡言 胆小呆滞 只吃长棍面包的国家生活吧
dumb-cheese-snail-baguette land.
因为你现在还没有女朋友 你不会懂
Now, now, just because you don’t have a girlfriend.
我太忙了没有时间交女朋友
I'm way too busy for a girlfriend.
总有一天你会有的
One day you'll make time.
到时候 你心里只有她的身影
You'll think of nothing else.
你会遇到一个人 会每天都沉浸在
You'll meet someone, and spend your days,
梦想着再次将她拥入怀中的感觉
dreaming of the moments you can hold them in your arms again.
这就是爱
That's love.
荒谬
Ridiculous.
我画完了
Finished.
我让你画犹太人住的地方
I said to draw where Jews live.
你画的却是我的头像
This is just a stupid picture of my head.
是啊 那就是我们住的地方
Yeah, that's where we live.
里尔克
Rilke.
这个蠢货诗人的书在哪里
Where are you poetry-writing dumbheads?
不错 你的想法非常好 小兔子
Yes, great thinking, Rabbit.
我们将利用这些书来做一层假地板
We'll use all of these books to make a fake floor
当她走过来会直接掉进满是
that she'll fall through straight into a pit full of
食人鱼、岩浆和培根的陷阱
piranhas and lava and bacon.
她不会知道是谁袭击了她
She won't know what hit her.
你嘘我
You shush, shush me.
我们找本书就走 图书馆不可以大声说话
Let's get a book and let's go, libraries are dumb.
好的 我们现在做的真是件伟大的事
Yeah, this is a really good idea what we are doing right now.
如果她真用心了这会让她的心碎成两瓣的
If she had a heart, this would break it clean in two.
有件事我要告诉你
I have something to tell you.
我找到一封你未婚夫内森以前写的信
I came across an old letter from Nathan, your fiancée.
是寄给你的
Addressed to you.
你在胡说些什么
What, the hell, are you talking about?
我读给你听
I'll just read it.
亲爱的艾尔莎 我实在是难以启齿
Dear Elsa, this is hard for me to say,
我不想和你结婚了
but I don't want to marry you anymore.
我遇到另一个女孩 我们彼此非常相爱并且亲吻了对方
I found a new woman, and we love a lot, and do the tongue kiss.
就像我最爱的诗人描写的那样
It's like my favorite poet Rilke says,
真正的相爱 要让彼此自由
We need, in love, to practice only this: letting each other go.
现在你自由了 在此向你说再见 抱歉
So, goodbye and sorry about letting you go.
你的前未婚夫
From Nathan, your ex-fiancée.
附言：我早就不打仗了
P.S. I am not really in the resistance.
我一直在向你撒谎 现在我只是个失业的胖子
I was lying. I'm unemployed and quite fat now.
不用开门 我忘记了还有第二封给你的信
Don't open the door, but I, actually, forgot that there was a second letter.
亲爱的艾尔莎 我想告诉你我现在不想和你分手了
Dear Elsa, I just wanted to let you know that I don't want to break up with you now.
我改变主意了 因为我不想你因为我而自杀
I changed my mind because I don't want you to kill yourself over me.
过去很多女孩子这么做过 这让我感到十分内疚
Which a couple of girls have done in the past, and it's pretty stressful.
我想你好好的生活下去
I need you to stay alive.
感谢上帝有个小男孩可以照顾你
Thank God you've been taken care of by that kid,
我敢说这个男孩比他的同龄人更优秀 更勇敢
who I must say is a remarkable young man beyond his years, and brave too.
总有一天我们会结婚的
And let’s still get married sometime,
尽管我现在一无所有
even though I am truly unemployed and have nothing going for me.
你亲爱的内森
Yours, Nathan.
-贝多芬  -爱因斯坦
- Beethoven. - Einstein.
-巴赫   -格什温
- Bach. - Gerschwin.
布拉姆斯 瓦格纳 莫扎特
Brahms. Wagner. Mozart.
这是你知道的所有的音乐家吗
Musicians, is that all you have?
里尔克
Rilke.
当然还有你最爱的犹太人之母里尔克
Of course, your favorite, Rilke. Jewish mother.
-还有迪特里希  -霍迪尼
- Dietrich, then. - Houdini.
不 这不可能
No, that's impossible!
小兄弟你就信了吧 不信你去问毕加索、莫迪利亚尼
Believe it brother. Just ask Pissaro, Modigliani,
曼雷 格特鲁德 摩西还有他们至高无上的主耶稣 阿门
Man Ray, Gertrude Stein, Mr. Moses, and the king of them all Jesus Christi, Amen.
你说的都是些老名字
You’re just saying any old name now.
我从来没听说过这些人 现在我听够了
I’ve never heard of these people, and now I’m fed up.
嘿
Hey.
如果你再看到他写的信 你会告诉我吗
If you find any more of those letters, would you let me know?
当然会了 就这样吧 再见
Sure. Okay. Bye.
过去这河岸边都是恋爱中的情侣
These banks used to be full of lovers.
他们在这里唱歌 跳舞
There was dancing and singing and...
充满浪漫
Romance.
现在没有时间去浪漫了
There's no time for romance!
我们在打仗
We're at war!
浪漫永远在身边
There's always time for romance.
有一天你会遇到你的意中人
Someday you'll meet someone special.
为什么每个人都告诉我这些
Why does everyone keep telling me that?
谁还告诉过你
Who else tells you that?
所有人
Everyone.
总之 这是蠢货的想法
Anyway, it was a stupid idea.
你才是蠢货
You're stupid.
爱是这个世界上最强大的东西
Love is the strongest thing in the world.
我觉得这世上金属才最坚硬无比
I think you’ll find that metal is the strongest thing in the world,
还有炸药和肌肉也很厉害
followed closely by dynamite and then muscles.
除此之外我还没见过更厉害的东西
Besides, I wouldn’t even know it if I saw it.
天呢 你的鞋带又没系好
Surprise, surprise. Your shoelaces are undone again.
乔乔 当爱来临的时候你就会明白了
Jojo, you'll know when that happens.
你会感受到爱的力量
You'll feel it.
爱也是一种痛苦
It's a pain.
我打赌我只会屁股痛
In my arse, I bet.
是你的肚子痛 就像里面飞满了蝴蝶一样
In your tummy. Like it full of butterflies.
好恶心
Yuck.
是的 好恶心
Yeah, yuck.
行了 希特勒 我们走吧
Come on, Shitler, let’s get a move on.
嘿
Hey!
你怎么了 先生 我好担心你
What's wrong with you? I'm worried about you, man.
你又喝多了吗
Are you drunk? Again?
快点啦
Come on.
你能不能松开
Can you please untie...
你真的长胖了
You are really getting fat.
我没有
I'm not...
要不我把你留在这 好吗
You know what, why don't I just leave you here, okay?
我明天再来这接你回去 行吗
And I'll come and get you tomorrow. Okay, how about that?
你就当你是个大人 亲爱的
You think you are adult, darling.
明天早上我在家门口等你
I'll meet you back at the house, I think, tomorrow morning.
你成长的太快了 不像个10岁的孩子
You’re growing up too fast. A ten-year old shouldn’t be
这个年纪不该庆祝战争 讨论政治
celebrating war and talking politics.
你这个年纪应该在爬树 然后不小心从树上掉下来才对
You should be climbing trees, and then falling out of those trees.
但是元首说过 当我们赢得战争的时候
But the Führer says, when we win,
年轻人将会统治世界
it is us, young boys, who will rule the world.
德国在消亡 我们会输了这场战争
The Reich is dying, we are going to lose the war,
到时候我们干什么去
and then what are you going to do?
生活就是一份赠礼 我们要过好每一天
Life is a gift. We must celebrate it.
我们应该跳着舞感谢上帝赋予我们生命
We have to dance to show God we are grateful to be alive.
我才不跳舞呢
Well, I won't dance.
那些没有工作的人才跳舞
Dancing is for people, who don't have a job.
自由的人才跳舞
Dancing is for people who are free.
跳跳舞可以让你忘了所有这些
It's an escape from all of this.
好 那你可以一路跳回家
Well, you are free to dance your way home.
我骑车回去
I'll ride.
那可不行
Oh, no, you don't.
谁也拦不住我
No one can stop me!
♪妈妈 我亲爱的妈妈♪
♪ Mama, ich rufe dich an, oh Mama ♪
♪终有那么一天♪
♪ Doch einst kommt der Tag ♪
♪我会告诉你♪
♪ Wo ich Dir sag ♪
♪我已成为一个男子汉♪
♪ Ich bin ein grosser Mann ♪
欢迎回家孩子们  快回家亲亲你们的母亲吧
Welcome home boys. Now go home and kiss your mothers.
♪你可以放心♪
♪ Und ruhe dich aus ♪
♪你已为我付出太多♪
♪ Du hast schon genug getan ♪
恐怕今天没有内森的来信了
No news from Nathan today, I’m afraid.
他很可能在做什么有趣的事情  比如读读书 长长胡子
He’s probably doing something amazing, like reading a book or growing a beard.
怎么了
What’s wrong?
你想让我跟你说说犹太人吗
Do you want me to tell you about the Jews?
无所谓
I don't care.
最初我们住在洞穴里 在地球中心很深很深的地方
In the beginning, we used to live in caves, deep, deep in the center of the Earth.
等一下
Wait.
那地方很吓人 到处都是奇奇怪怪的生物 不过他们有个共同点
Scary places, full of strange and wonderful creatures all with one thing in common...
偷割别人的小JJ
Stealing the ends of penises.
不是 你个傻子 他们都热爱艺术
No, you idiot. The love of art.
不割别人的小JJ吗
No cutting penises off?
你到底听不听我讲了
Do you want the story or not?
你可以继续讲 但我知道小JJ的事是真的
You may continue, but I know it’s true, the penis thing.
你们犹太教教士拿它做耳塞
Rabbis use them for earplugs.
不说这个了 经过很多年的努力
And moving on. After many years of developing
精通魔法和咒语 我们慢慢地搬出洞穴住到了城镇里
magic and spells, we slowly moved out of the caves and into the towns.
不过当中有些人依然留在洞穴里 以动物的样子示人
Some of us stayed in the caves though, in animal bodies.
就像黏菌怪那样吗
Which are blobs or something?
我画给你看
I’ll draw them for you.
用彩笔画会更好看些
It'd be better with color.
犄角在哪儿
Where’s the horns?
在头发下面
Under the hair.
你的犄角呢
Where are yours?
我太年轻了 要到21岁才会长出犄角
I’m too young. They grow when you turn 21.
如今我们生活在普通人中间  通常我们会抢一套房子来住
These days we live among normal people, but often we take over a house
睡觉的时候我们就倒挂在天花板上 像蝙蝠一样
and hang from the ceiling when we sleep, like bats.
还有一件事 我们可以读取彼此的想法
And another thing is - we can read each others’ minds.
天呐 能读出所有人的想法吗 德国人的呢
Oh my God! Everyone’s minds? What about German minds?
德国人的不行 他们脑壳太厚了 我们没法穿透
No, their heads are too thick for us to penetrate.
就像小鸟一样 我们真正的语言就像是在唱歌
Like birds, our true language sounds like singing.
我们还喜欢亮晶晶的东西
And we also attracted to shiny things.
水晶 玻璃 还有金子
Crystals, glass and gold.
喜欢亮晶晶的东西
Attracted to shiny things.
你们还喜欢丑陋的东西 犹太人喜欢丑陋的东西
But also ugly things. Jews love ugliness.
这也是我们在学校学到的
That’s another thing we learned in school.
你也喜欢的 对吧 丑陋的东西
You love them, yes? Ugly things?
嗨
Hi.
你们俩好像相处的不错啊
You two seem to be getting on well.
我只是去确认一下她是不是还活着
I was just making she was still alive.
这关你什么事
What do you care?
不关我的事 我只是不希望家里有个死人
I don’t, I just don't want a dead person in my house.
你希望这样吗
How would you like it?
我乐意这样 请让我家里多几个死人吧
I'd love it. More dead people in my house, please.
你看 你们俩一起度过的这些时间
Look, just all the time you two are spending together,
让我感到非常不舒服
it's making me feel very uncomfortable.
一开始是你提议的
You suggested it in the first place.
是我吗
Did I?
-是的  -哦 对 确实是我
- Yeah. - Oh, yeah, I did.
再说了 我是为了写书
Besides, it’s for the book.
天呐 你说的对 对不起 是我的错吗
Oh my God. You are right. I'm sorry. Did I make it weird?
现在咱俩有点闹别扭了 是吗 我们不应该闹别扭的
It's weird now, isn't it? It shouldn't be weird between us.
这一切都不该感到别扭才对
None of this should be weird.
没事 我就是有点累 我要睡觉了
It's fine. I'm just tired. I'm going to bed.
好的 我这是在替你暖被窝呢
Yeah, I was just keeping your bed warm for you,
好朋友就应该这样
'cause that's what real friends do.
嗨 你觉得这身制服怎么样？
Hey, what do you think about this uniform?
我不太确定裤子臀部这里是不是该更肥一些
I'm not sure about the hips on the pants. Should they be bigger?
看上去挺好的
You look great.
谢谢
Thank you.
听着 乔乔 我可以给你提一些真正的好建议吗
Now, listen, Jojo, can I give you some really good advice?
如果你看清了她的想法
When you see what's in her mind,
知道她想让你产生什么想法
and where she's trying to make you go in your mind.
你心里一定要反着来
In your mind, you must go the other way.
你明白我在说什么吗 别让她控制了你的意念
You're getting what I'm saying? Do not let her put you in a brain prison.
亲爱的乔乔 那样的事是绝对永远不能发生在德国人身上的
That, dear Jojo, is one thing that cannot and must not ever ever happen to a German!
别让她摆布你一个德国人的头脑
Do not let your German brain be bossed around!
我不会让她随意摆布我这颗德国人的头脑的 元首
I won't let her boss my German brain around, Mein Führer.
尽量不要
Try not to.
我想你的书里已经收集了很多不错的信息
Now, I think you've got a lot of good information in your book.
是时候公之于众了 你觉得呢
It's time to show it to the world, don't you think?
是的
Yeah.
阿道夫
Adolf?
你觉得我丑吗
Do you think I'm ugly?
丑
Yes.
他睡着了吗
Is he asleep?
他真是与众不同
He's different.
他起疑心了  认为英加的鬼魂一直在这儿
He suspects something. He thinks Inga's ghost ends up here.
看到你就让我想起她 真的
You remind me of her. You really do.
我真想看到她长成一个大姑娘
I would love to have seen her grow into a woman.
可我现在只能看着你
But I'll have to watch you instead.
我不知道大姑娘该是什么样子
I don't know anything about being a woman.
是这样的吗 可以做一些事情 比如喝酒
Is that what it is? You do things, like drink wine?
当然 可以喝酒
Sure, you'll drink.
高兴的时候喝点香槟
Champagne if you are happy.
不高兴的时候也喝点香槟
Champagne if you are sad.
可以开车 想赌钱也可以
You drive a car, gamble if you want.
可以有钻饰了 可以学怎么开枪
Own diamonds. Learn how to fire a gun.
可以去摩洛哥旅行 带着你的爱人们
You can travel to Morocco. Take up lovers.
折磨折磨他们
Make them suffer.
与老虎对视
You look a tiger in the eye.
能放心的交付信任 成年的大姑娘就是这样
And trust without fear - that's what it is to be a woman.
你是怎么做的呢
How do you do that?
你怎么知道有的人是可以信任的
How do you know you can trust someone?
信任他们就是了
You trust them.
晚安
Goodnight.
你刚才说的这些事 你都做过吗
All those other things. Did you do that stuff?
去摩洛哥旅行  还有其他的事情
You know, go to Morocco, and the rest.
没有 我从来没跟老虎对视过
No, I've never looked a tiger in the eye.
芬克尔 我说用来防守敌人的德牧是指德国牧羊犬
Finkel, I meant we'd need dogs for when the city is attacked, not, actual
而不是德国牧羊人
German shepherds.
让他们出去
Get them out of here.
让他们出去 立刻
Get them out of here! Now!
马上
Now!
请出去吧 谢谢
Move along please. Thank you.
很抱歉冲你大吼大叫了
I'm sorry for yelling at you.
-我真是太蠢了  -不不
- I feel so stupid. - No, no.
只能怪狗和人用同一个名字
It's a silly name for a dog,
我应该说清楚点的 你工作一直都干的不错
I should've been more clear. You're doing a great job.
丹克
Danke.
嗨 孩子
Hiya, kid.
我们能为您做点什么呢 贝茨勒先生
How can we help you today, Master Betzler?
最近怎么样 跟我说说
What's up? Work with me.
如果有人交出来一个犹太人 他会得到奖章或什么吗
If someone turned in a Jew, would they get a medal or something?
噢 犹太人 犹太人...你还在想着这帮人呢
Oh, Jews, Jews... You still going on about those people?
你也知道 这座城市随时将遭受攻击 我正在备战
You know, I'm preparing the city for imminent invasion, right?
我在尝试全球防御策略
I'm tying the planet defense strategy.
西边要抵御美国 东边要抵御俄罗斯
I've got Americans to the West. Got Russians to the East.
我有个朋友遇到了几个俄罗斯人然后被他们吃了
My friend once met some Russians and they ate him.
核桃代表哪国
Who's the walnuts?
核桃只是核桃 孩子
Walnuts are just walnuts, kid.
你想说什么
What do you want to talk about?
我现在知道了很多关于犹太人的事
Well, I am learning a lot about Jews.
你知道吗 他们真的会读心术
Did you know, Jews can read each others' minds?
他们睡觉的时候是挂在屋顶上的 就像蝙蝠一样
And when they sleep, they hang from the ceiling, like bats.
这太有意思了 你是从哪儿知道这些的
That's fascinating, where did you come by this information?
研究所得 我正在写一本书
Research. I'm writing a book.
噢 恭喜你了 书名叫什么
Oh, congratulations. What's it called?
《哟呵 犹太人》  这本书是曝光犹太人的
"Yoohoo Jew". It's an exposé on Jews.
书名也可以叫《你是谁 犹太人》
You could also call it "Who are you, Jew?".
叫《犹太人新闻》怎么样
What about "Jews News"?
你的想象力真是太棒了
You do have a wonderful imagination on you.
-这些是真的  -是 当然是真的
- It's real. - Yeah, of course, it's real.
我在你这个年纪的时候 我还有个想象的朋友 叫科尼
When I was your age I had an imaginary friend, called Conny.
我睡着的时候他总在我床上尿尿 给我惹了不少麻烦
He used to wet my bed when I was asleep. He got me in so much trouble.
嘿 到这儿来 你也许想看看我都在忙些什么
Hey, come here, you might like to check out what I'm working on.
作为这次进攻准备工作的一部分 我正在重新设计我的制服
As part of our preparations for the invasion, I'm redesigning my uniform.
可以放上羽毛增加动力 闪闪的颜色可以迷惑敌人
Got the feathers for air dynamics. The sparkly color to dazzle the enemy.
这靴子 纯粹装饰
The boots, purely decorative.
这个
And this.
这是加特林机枪 装有无线电
This is a Gatling gun, mounted with a radio,
它们可以发出恼人的音乐来干扰敌人
which emits annoying music to dishearten the enemy.
顺便说一下 这都是受版权保护的
This is all copyrighted, by the way.
这就意味着你不能抄袭它
That means you can't copy it.
别想打歪脑筋 孩子
Yeah, don't give me ideas, kid.
那群孩子告诉我你父亲在外参战
The kids are telling me that your father is away fighting?
所以你现在似乎是这个房子的男主 感觉如何
So, it appears you are now the man of the house, how is that going?
还好
It's okay.
哈
Ja?
所以你今天给我安排了什么活
So, what jobs do you have for me today?
老实说只有一个活
I only got have one, I wouldn't lie.
跟你之前做的有点不一样 但是
It's a bit of a step-down from what you used to, but
我们现在很需要人手
we need all hands on deck right now.
金属捐给希特勒
Metal for Hitler.
捐出锅盆为胜利
Pots and pans for the war effort.
金属达人满街跑 为寻锅碗瓢盆金
Here comes the metal man, looking for your pots and pans.
为希特勒捐金属
Metal for Hitler.
锅碗瓢盆 来者不拒
Pots and pans.
解放德国
Free Germany.
乔乔
Jojo?
约克
Yorki?
嗨
Hi!
你现在是军人了吗
You're a soldier now?
乐意效劳
At your service.
但是你只有11岁
But you're only 11.
我知道
I know.
-我可以看看吗  -当然
- May I? - Yeah, sure.
这是纸做的吗
Is that paper?
我起初也以为是纸 但它只是类纸型材料
That's what I thought at first too, but it's "paper-like".
这是种新型材料 由我们的顶尖科学家发明的
It's the latest material, invented by our top scientists.
哇 真让我大开眼界
Well, I'm impressed.
嘿 约克
Hey, Yorki.
我抓到一个犹太人 一个真人
I caught a Jew. A real one.
犹太人吗
A Jew?
我上个月看到他们抓了些藏在树林里的犹太人
I saw some that they caught, hiding in the Forrest last month.
在我看来 我觉得没必要这样大惊小怪
Personally, I didn't see what all the fuss was about.
他们看起来一点都不吓人 就和普通人一样
They weren't at all scary and seemed, kind of, normal.
差点忘了正事 我得走了
I'm getting distracted. I got to go.
拜拜
Bye.
天呐 穿着这身跑起来真费劲
Oh my God. It's so hard to run in this thing.
我找到一些彩铅
I found these.
你拿去吧 有可能是坏的
You can have them. They're, probably, broken.
没有别的意思
Doesn't mean anything.
或许你可以在我的书上画些东西
Maybe, you can draw something for my book.
我可以再画一次你
I could draw you again.
没有人想看残疾人的画像
No one wants to see pictures of cripples.
你不是残疾人
You're not a cripple.
再说 真正的艺术家是不会在意这些的
Besides, true artists don't see that stuff.
你是指盲人艺术家吧
Blind artists, you mean.
没关系 我会接受永远没有女孩子亲吻的事实的
It's fine. I'll just accept I'll be one of those guys who never get to kiss a girl.
你会被亲吻的 乔乔
You will be kissed, Jojo.
你想我吻你吗
Do you want me to kiss you?
好
Okay.
说两点
Two things.
首先
Thing number one.
纳粹和犹太人像我们这样玩在一起是不合法的 更别提亲吻了
It's illegal for Nazis and Jews to hang out like we do, let alone kiss.
其次
Thing number two.
这只是出于同情亲一下 根本不算吻
It'd just be a sympathy kiss, which doesn't count.
你不是纳粹
You're not a Nazi.
我很喜欢纳粹十字符号 我认为这是一个很好的证明
I'm massively into swastikas, so, I think, that's a pretty good sign right there.
乔乔 你不是纳粹
You’re not a Nazi, Jojo.
你只是个十岁的孩子 一个喜欢十字符号和奇装异服的孩子
You’re a 10-year-old kid, who likes swastikas and likes dressing up in a funny uniform,
你想成为俱乐部的一份子 但你不是他们
and wants to be part of a club. But you’re not one of them.
好吧
Okay.
我们就求同存异 好吗
Let's just agree to disagree, all right?
不是纳粹
Not a Nazi.
好脏的犹太人啊
What a dirty Jew!
赶快 去藏起来 快
Come on, hide! Hurry, go!
希特勒万岁
Heil Hitler.
我先自我介绍一下 我是福尔肯海姆国家秘密警察队的赫尔曼迪尔兹上尉
Allow me to introduce myself, I am Captain Herman Deertz of Falkenheim Gestapo.
和我一起的还有穆勒先生 容克先生 克鲁姆先生和弗罗施先生
With me Herr Müller, Herr Junker, Herr Klum, and Herr Frosch.
我们可以进来吗
May we come in?
非常感谢
Thank you so much.
希特勒万岁
Heil Hitler.
嗨 乔乔
Hey, Jojo.
嗨 各位 很高兴见到你们
Hey, guys. Good to see you.
我的自行车爆胎了  只能一路扛着来
My bicycle got a flat tire, so I carried it.
克伦森多队长
Captain Klenzendorf?
希特勒万岁
Heil Hitler!
你认识弗雷迪·芬克尔吗?
You know Freddie Finkel?
希特勒万岁
Heil Hitler.
我错过了什么吗
So, did I miss anything?
没有 没有 我们只是和这个男孩 还有你打招呼
No, no. We we just heil Hiltering the boy and then heil Hiltering yourself,
当然还有弗雷迪·芬克尔
and then, of course, heil Hiltering Freddie Finkel,
现在我们还在例行检查中
and now we in the midst of a routine inspection.
队长你又为何到此呢
And what brings you here, captain?
我们正好经过 觉得应该给这个男孩留一些宣传册
We were just passing by, and we thought we'd drop off some pamphlets for the boy.
他为我们工作
He works for us.
我明白了
I see.
你呢
And yourself?
你知道是怎么回事 我们每天都会接到电话
You know how it is. Every day we take a call.
您好 是盖世太保吗 我认为这里有共党
Hello, is that the Gestapo? I believe there's a Communist,
藏在我的冰箱后面
hiding behind my fridge.
我们去搜查了 结果只是些模型
We go around to investigate, it's just some mold.
每次都差不多
So, not far off.
这都是工作的一部分
It's all part of the job.
我就喜欢这样的小孩卧室
Now, this is my kind of little boy's bedroom.
噢真棒 他贴在那儿呢
Oh, yes. There he is.
你和你朋友可能听过希特勒只有一个蛋蛋的谣言 简直是无稽之谈
You and your friends may have heard a rumor that Hitler only has one ball, this is nonsense.
他明明有四个
He has four.
所以你在希特勒青年团办公室当志愿者 是吗
So, you are volunteering at the Hitlerjugend office, yes?
是的
Yes.
你太棒了
Good for you.
我希望更多的年轻男孩都能有你这样盲目的狂热
I wish more of our young boys had your blind fanaticism.
这些笨蛋究竟在楼上做什么 我们上去看看吧
What on earth are those oafs up to? Why don’t we go upstairs and see, yes?
你知道你母亲在哪里吗
Do you know where your mother is?
不知道
No.
我想她在镇上
I think she's in town.
她在家待的时间长吗
Has she been spending much time at home?
她很忙的
She is quite busy.
是吗
Is she?
我很高兴看到你穿着青少年团的制服 但是
Well, I'm pleased to see that you're wearing your Jugend uniform, but
你的配刀呢
where is your knife?
德军刺刀必须随身携带 它在哪里
You must always carry your DJ knife, where is it?
我
I...
放在……
Left...
在这里
It's here.
你是谁
And who might you be?
你又是谁
你在我家干什么
And what are you doing in my house?
你也住在这里吗
You live here too?
我是他的姐姐 英加
I'm his sister, Inga.
希特勒万岁
Heil Hitler.
我不知道你还有个姐姐 乔纳斯
I did not know you have a sister, Johannes.
有的时候他宁愿我死了
Sometimes he'd prefer if I was dead.
是不是 小怪人
Isn't that right, little Frankenstein?
现在没有必要去攻击他难看的身体缺陷
Now, now, there's no need to attack his hideous physical deformity.
那是战伤
That is a war wound.
可是
But...
他的刀为何在你那儿
Why do you have his knife?
我在守卫我的房间 因为他老是想进去
I’m guarding my room, because he refuses to stay out of it.
你房里藏了什么
What do you have hidden in there?
你懂的 女孩子的东西
You know, girl's stuff.
我可以看一下吗
May I?
当然可以
Naturally.
你看 我们要处理很多报告
You see, we deal with an inordinate number of reports,
斥责和做普查 当然
denunciations, and general investigations, and, of course,
我们确实对犯罪问题和反政党情绪感兴趣
we are indeed interested in problems of crime and anti party sentiment.
但我们还是有个更大的担心 那就是那群人
But we still have one greater concern. That's of the Goldilocksies,
他们偷偷摸摸 吃别人的食物
sneaking around, eating other people's food.
睡别人床 这些都是很粗鲁的行为
Sleeping in the beds, it really is quite rude.
我想看看你的证件 可以吗
I don't suppose I could see your papers, could I?
证件 贝茨勒小姐 请快一点 我们时间不多
Papers, Miss Betzler. Quickly, please, we don't have all day.
好的 可以
Yes, of course.
这张照片你几岁拍的
How old are you in this photo?
照了有3年了 我当时14岁
They’re 3 years old, I was 14.
出生日期呢
Date of birth?
1929年5月1日
1st of May. 1929.
正确 谢谢你 英加
Correct. Thank you, Inga.
换张新照片吧 你这张看起来跟鬼一样
Get a new photo, you look like a ghost in this one.
等等
Wait!
这是什么
What is this?
《哟吼 犹太人》
"Yoohoo Jew".
告诉我谁做的
Tell me who did this.
我做的
I did.
它记载了犹太人的一切 包括他们思想行为
It's an exposé on Jews. How they think, behave,
以及外貌 是给元首准备的礼物
look, it'll be a gift to the Führer.
伙计们 你们得看看这个
Guys, you have to see this.
看这个 他有一个尾巴
Look at this one. He has a tail.
这里面的一个 像蝙蝠一样倒挂着
There's one of them, hanging upside down like a bat.
这儿的一个 画的是他们的头
This one here, it is a drawing of their heads.
是谁在操控他们脑袋上的机器
And who is operating the machinery of their brains?
是魔鬼 真是有趣
The Devil. It's funny 'cause it's true.
看这个愚蠢的犹太人 他们头上都长着角
Look at this little stupid Jew. There they are with horns.
这是什么
What is this?
杀死内森 内森去死 杀死内森的方法
Die Nathan, die. Ways of killing Nathan.
内森 正被蛇折磨着 被棍子戳
Nathan, being tortured by snakes. Poked with sticks.
被当做炮火发射
Being fired from a cannon.
被冷冻
Just being cold names.
内森正被古董自行车的巨大前轮碾压着
Nathan, being crushed under the wheel of penny farthing bicycle.
请问谁是内森
Who is Nathan, please?
只是一个男孩
Just some boy.
内森被架在火上烤着
Nathan, being roasted over an open fire.
它提醒我了 我们该回去了
It reminds me. We must get back.
那个家伙还被我们吊着呢
Remember, 'cause we left that guy, hanging up.
谢谢你的书 今天的时间没有浪费
Thank you for this, you have really made my day.
希望你可以继续创作
I do hope you continue with it.
当然 如果你发现任何可疑之处
And, of course, if you see anything suspicious
给我们打电话
give us a ring.
再见
Good day.
希特勒万岁
Heil Hitler.
很高兴见到你 英加
Nice to meet you, Inga.
在家待着 乔乔
Stay home, Jojo.
照看好家人 照看好这把刀
Look after your family. Look after this knife.
艾尔莎 你骗过了他们
Elsa, you fooled them!
是5月7日
May 7th.
什么
What?
她出生日期是7号
She was born on the 7th.
不是1号
Not the 1st.
他帮了我们
He was helping us.
他们还会回来的
They'll be back.
他们会发现真正的英加已经死了 我也会没命的
They'll figure out she's dead, then I'll be dead.
没有人真的知道英加死了
Nobody really knows Inga died.
你可以替代成为她
You could be her.
妈妈回来后我会告诉她一切
I'll tell Mama everything when she gets home.
我了解你 我们是朋友
That I know you, and that we're friends.
犹太人和纳粹不是朋友
Jew and Nazi are not friends.
孩子 这完全是次突击搜查 介意解释一下么
Man, that was a complete bust. Mind explaining that?
她不是……
She's not...
她看起来不像坏人
She doesn't seem like a bad person.
我开始怀疑你对我和组织的忠诚了
I am beginning to question your loyalty to myself and the party.
你宣称自己爱国
You call yourself a patriot?
好 证据在哪里
Yet, where is the evidence?
德国士兵是因为需要才诞生的
The German soldier was born out of necessity.
德国存亡取决于这些年轻人的激情
Germany depends on the passion of these young men.
随时准备为国捐躯 慷慨就义
Passion and readiness to fall for the Fatherland,
尽管那些盟军暴徒在做徒劳的斗争
despite the futile efforts of ally war profiteers,
他们尽派一些松散的军队傻乎乎的冲进狼窝
who send their ill-prepared armies, clumsily, into the lair of the wolf.
只有直面敌人 毫不退缩的勇士
And only zealous men, who stand steadfast in the face of the enemy
才会被德国历史永远铭记
will be etched in German memory forever.
由你自己来决定你是想被大家记住
And it is up to you to decide if you want to be remembered,
还是想消失得无影无踪
or disappear without a trace,
就像掉进无边沙漠的一粒尘埃
like a pitiful grain of sand into a dessert of insignificance.
说白了
To put it plainly.
镇定下来 分清轻重缓急
Get your shit together and sort out your priorities.
你已经十岁了 乔乔
You're 10, Jojo.
开始像样点
Start acting like it.
你知道吗
Did you know?
她没有告诉我太多事情
She didn't tell me much.
只说她和朋友在一起工作
Only that she worked with her friends
你的父亲某种程度也参与了
and your father was, somehow, involved from afar.
不 他在战场上打仗
No, he's fighting in the war.
她说战争结束了 他就会回家的
She said he'll be home as soon as the war is over.
因为一些很明显的原因 她并不想告诉你一切
She didn't want to tell you anything for obvious reasons.
因为她讨厌我
Because she hated me.
因为我是纳粹 我是敌人
'Cause I'm a Nazi. I'm the enemy.
她不想让你知道那些可能会让你陷入麻烦的事情
She didn't want you to know anything that could get you in trouble.
但是我现在一无所有了
But now I have nothing.
无依无靠
No one.
我上一次见到我的父母亲还是在车站
The last time I saw my parents was at the station.
他们被装上火车
They were put on the train.
我跑了
I ran.
慢慢的找回城的路
Slowly, found my way back to the city.
我父亲的一个朋友把我藏起来
A friend of my father's hid me.
然后另外一个朋友 朋友的朋友
Then, another friend, then friends of friends...
直到你母亲把我带进来
Till your mother took me in.
我在这里待到现在
And so far I am still here.
但是我的父母亲去了一个不能回来的地方
But my parents went to a place you don't come back from.
等你自由后 你想做的第一件事是什么
What's the first thing you'll do when you're free?
跳舞
Dance.
♪每个人都得活着♪
♪ Everybody's gotta live ♪
♪每个人都会死♪
♪ And everybody's gonna die ♪
♪大家都得活着♪
♪ Everybody's gotta live ♪
我♪想你知道原因♪
♪ I think you know the reason why ♪
♪有时候会变得很好♪
♪ Sometimes the going gets so good ♪
♪有时候也会相当艰难♪
♪ Then again it gets pretty rough ♪
♪但是宝贝 当我拥抱你♪
♪ But when I have you in my arms baby ♪
♪你知道这远远不够♪
♪ You know I just can't, I just can't get enough ♪
♪噢耶♪
♪ Oh yeah ♪
♪每个人都得活着♪
♪ Everybody's gotta live ♪
♪每个人都会死♪
♪ And everybody's gonna die ♪
♪每个人都试着过幸福的生活♪
♪ Everybody's try to have a good time ♪
♪我相信你知道理由♪
♪ I think you know the reason why ♪
♪我仿佛看到了数不清的日落♪
♪ I feel like I've seen just about a million sunsets ♪
♪她说只要你在我就永远不会离开♪
♪ She said if you're with me I'll never go away ♪
♪当我停下来的时候 我再看了一眼我的宝贝♪
♪ That's when I stopped and I took another look at my baby ♪
♪她说只要你在 我就永远不会离开♪
♪ She said if you're with me I'll never go away ♪
♪因为♪
♪ Because ♪
♪每个人都得活着♪
♪ Everybody's gotta live ♪
♪每个人都会死亡♪
♪ And everybody's gonna die ♪
♪每个人都得活着♪
♪ Everybody's gotta live ♪
♪在你知道理由前♪
♪ Before you know the reason why ♪
♪每个人都得活着♪
♪ Everybody's gotta live ♪
♪在你知道理由前♪
♪ Before you know the reason why ♪
约克
Yorki?
乔乔
Jojo!
我的天
Oh God.
乔乔 我想死你了
Jojo! Oh, I've missed you!
为你妈妈的事情感到难过
Sorry about your mama.
我听到这件事的时候哭了好久
I cried for ages, when I heard what happened.
外面发生什么事了
What's going on out here?
是俄罗斯人 乔乔 他们攻打过来了
The Russians, Jojo. They're coming.
美国人从另外一边来了
And the Americans from the other way.
还有英国 中国
And England, and China.
非洲 印度 好多国家都来了
And Africa, and India. The whole world is coming.
帮我推这些弹药
Help me with this ammo.
我们要怎么做
And how are we doing?
真糟糕 我们的盟友只有日本人
Terribly. Our only friends are the Japanese.
也就我俩才这么说 他们没有雅利安人那么优秀
And just between you and me, they don’t look very Aryan.
你还记得那个犹太人吗 我跟你说过的那个
Remember that Jew, I told you about?
-嗯  -我还和她在一起
- Oh yeah. - I still have her.
她现在算是我的女朋友了
She's, basically, my girlfriend now.
噢 真为你高兴 乔乔 你有女朋友了
Oh, good for you, Jojo. A girlfriend.
问题是 你懂得 她是犹太人
But, you know, she is Jewish.
现在有比犹太人更需要担心的事情 乔乔
There are bigger things to worry about than Jews, Jojo.
外面都是俄国人
There are Russians somewhere out there.
他们比其他人都要可怕
They are worse than anyone.
我听说他们吃小孩 和狗发生关系
I heard they eat babies and have sex with dogs.
这很坏 不是吗
I mean, like, that's bad, right?
和狗发生关系
Sex with dogs?
是的 英国人也这样做
Yeah, the Englishmen do it too.
我们得在他们吃掉我们和糟蹋掉所有的狗之前制止他们
We have to stop them before they eat us and screw all our dogs.
真疯狂 希特勒死了 现在只能靠自己了
It's crazy. And now Hitler's gone. We're really on our own.
什么
What?
你没听说吗
You didn't hear?
他死了
He's dead.
他放弃反抗开枪自杀了
He gave up and blew his brains out.
不 这不可能
No! That's impossible.
对着脑袋开枪自杀的
Blew them out. His brains.
原来 他藏了很多秘密
Turns out, he was hiding a lot of stuff from us.
他背着我们做了很多坏事
Doing some really bad things behind everyone’s backs.
我不确定我们能否幸存下来
I'm not sure if we'll survive attacks.
好吧 过来
Okay. Come here.
看见那边那个美国人了吗 去给他一个拥抱
Okay. See that American there? Just go give him a hug.
上 跑起来 前进
Go! Run! Let's go!
噢 约克 约克
Oh, Yorki, Yorki.
好消息 你刚刚升官了而且有了自己的手枪
Great news, you've just been promoted and you get you own pistol.
去杀掉那些非我族的异类吧
Just go and shoot anybody who looks different to us.
好
Okay.
乔乔 你的制服呢
Jojo, where's your uniform?
给 把这件衣服穿上 这样他们就不会开枪打你了
Here, put this jacket on, so they know not to shoot you.
我们要把敌军杀个片甲不留
We must kill everything that we see.
希特勒万岁
Heil Hitler!
去死吧 魔鬼
Die, devil's tongue.
是 我们会搜查他的
Yeah, we'll check him.
嘿 嘿
Hey! Hey!
怎么了
What?
我不明白
I don't understand.
K队长
Captain K.
嘿 孩子 看看这场骚乱
Hiya, kid. Look at all this commotion.
发生什么了
What's happening?
发疯了 我的朋友 我们玩完了
Hysteria, my friend. We come to the end.
派对结束了
Party's over.
你害怕吗 别害怕
Are you scared? Don't be scared.
看着我
Look at me.
我为罗茜感到遗憾 她是个好人
I'm sorry about Rosie, she was a good person.
一个真正的好人
An actual good person.
好吗
Okay?
没事的 孩子
It's okay, kid.
我一直想告诉你 我觉得你的书很棒
I've been meaning to tell you. I think your book is really great.
我很抱歉嘲笑了它
I'm sorry for laughing at it.
非常有创意
Very creative.
过来 让我好好看看你
Come here, let's take a look at you.
你看起来不错 你没事的 孩子
You look good. You're okay, kid.
现在回家去照顾你的姐姐
Now, go home. Look after that sister of yours.
行吗
Okay?
滚开
Get away!
滚开 犹太人
Get away, Jew!
快滚开
Get away!
怎么回事
What's going on?
是个犹太人
It's a Jew!
闭嘴 你认识这个纳粹吗
Shut up! You know this Nazi?
他...
He...
我不认识这个肮脏的犹太人
I don't know this dirty Jew.
-滚远点 犹太人  -闭嘴 纳粹
- Get away, Jew! - Shut your mouth, Nazi!
-不  -你离开这儿
- No! - Get out of here!
回家去
Go home!
-放开他  -回家去
- Leave him alone! - Go home!
别待在这儿 回家去
Get out of here! Go home!
乔乔
Jojo?
约克
Yorki!
谢天谢地
Thank God!
我以为你死了呢
I thought you were dead.
没有 看来我还命不该绝
No, it seems like I can never die.
我要回家去看我的妈妈
I'm gonna go home to see my mother.
我需要一个拥抱
I need a cuddle.
一切都变得毫无意义
Nothing makes sense anymore.
是啊 现在可不是当纳粹的时机
Yeah, it's, definitely not a good time to be a Nazi.
嘿 现在战争结束了 至少你的女朋友自由了
Hey, so now the war is over, at least your girlfriend will be free.
她可以离开了
She can leave now.
有什么不对的吗
Is something wrong?
我得走了
I've got to go.
-好的  -抱歉
- Okay. - Sorry.
嗨 我回来了
Hi, I'm home.
外面发生了什么
What's going on out there?
什么外面
Out where?
屋子外面 傻瓜
Outside, dummy.
乔乔 发生了什么
Jojo, what's going on?
现在出去安全吗
Is it safe to come out?
乔乔 安全吗
Jojo, is it safe?
我能离开了吗
Can I leave?
不能
No.
你不能离开
You can't leave.
为什么
Why?
你只能呆在这
You have to stay here.
谁赢了
Who won?
和我在一起
With me.
乔乔 谁赢了 谁赢了这场战争
Jojo, who won? Who won the war?
我们赢了
We did.
德国赢了
Germany won the war.
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
亲爱的艾尔莎 我知道现在对你来说很艰难
Dear Elsa, I know it's hard for you at the moment.
我也知道你想放弃
And I know you feel like giving up.
但是你要继续坚持下去
But you have to carry on.
我和你的好朋友乔乔 设计了一个计划供你逃走
Me and your good friend Jojo, have devised a plan for you to escape.
所以 请听他说
So, please, listen to him.
他会帮你离开这
He's gonna help you to get out of there.
然后你就可以来巴黎见我了
And then you could come be with me in Paris.
不用担心乔乔
Don't worry about Jojo.
他会没事的
He'll be okay.
巴黎见  内森
See you in Paris. Nathan.
他死了
He's dead.
你说什么
Pardon?
内森
Nathan.
他去年死了  肺结核
He died last year. Tuberculosis.
好吧
Well...
那就奇怪了 这些是谁写给你的呢
That's weird. Who wrote these?
谢谢你 乔乔
Thank you, Jojo.
你对我真好
You've been so good to me.
事实上
Well... Thing is...
我爱你
I love you.
我知道你把我当弟弟 没关系
I know you think of me as a younger brother, which is fine.
然后
And...
反正你也挺老的
You're too old anyway.
但是
But...
天哪 这里真热
Man, it's quite hot in here.
我也爱你
I love you too.
-只是像弟弟一样疼爱  -对 像弟弟一样
- As a younger brother? - Yes, as a younger brother.
听着 我和假内森找到了一条逃跑路线
Look, me and fake Nathan have found a way for you to escape.
也许你可以相信下你的弟弟
Maybe, you can trust your younger brother?
也许吧
Maybe.
好的
Okay then.
收拾你的东西 我们走
Get your things together. We're leaving.
乔乔·贝茨勒 十岁半
Jojo Betzler. Ten and a half years old.
今天 尽你所能
Today, just do what you can.
你觉得你能去哪
Where, in a shit, do you think you're going?
-外面  -外面
- Out. - Out?
噢不 你不能
Oh no, you don't.
现在我们要待在这里 你要老老实实告诉我
Now, we gonna stay in here, and you gonna tell me exactly
你和阁楼里的那个东西到底怎么回事
what's going on with you and that thing it the attic.
她是人 不是东西
That thing is a girl.
你爱上她了 是吗
You're in love with her, aren't you?
是的
Yes.
-承认吧  -我刚刚说的是
- Admit it! - I just said yes.
我就知道
I knew it!
你们永远不能在一起的
It was never gonna work out.
她对你来说年纪太大了 而且你很丑
And you. No, she's too old for you. And you're ugly.
她会离开你的 你知道的 不是吗
No, she's gonna leave you, you know that, don't you?
所以接下来会是这样 你这个小混蛋
So, here's what's gonna happen, you little shit.
你要戴上这个 知道吗
You gonna put this on, okay?
你要忘记那个恶心的犹太母牛
You gonna forget about that disgusting Jewy cow up there.
并且回到我身边 我才是你的归属
And you gonna come back to me, where you belong.
明白吗
All right?
戴上它
Put it on!
然后 我们假装什么也没有发生
And then, we gonna pretend none of this ever happened.
听懂了吗
You got it?
跟我喊万岁 看在过去的份上 跟我喊万岁
Heil me? For old time sake? Heil me, little man.
不
No.
-跟我喊万岁  -不
- Heil me. - No.
就喊一声 求你了
Just a little heil. Please.
滚吧 希特勒
Fuck off, Hitler!
走吧
Come on.
噢 等一下
Oh, wait.
准备好了吗
Ready?
好了
Yeah.
外面危险吗
Is it dangerous out there?
极其危险
Extremely.
我们成功了
We made it.
我活该
Probably, deserved that.
我们现在做什么
What do we do now?
新浪微博 @摆渡字幕组 译制
关注微博 掌握最新字幕资源
摆渡字幕组翻译招募中 报名群:377256405